# Swarup Kumar Dey (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, JDBC, JSP, Servlet, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Ruby On Rails, HTML, CSS, AJAX



Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 2 Month(s) Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Engineering]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Java, JDBC, JSP, Servlet, Spring

Boot, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Ruby On Rails, HTML, CSS, AJAX

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

### Summary

Having 3+ years of experience in developing Web and Enterprise Applications using technologies Java / J2EE, Spring, and Restful Web Services.

Hands on experience in Core Java, J2ee, JDBC, JSP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap, AngularJS.

Working experience in Spring Boot and Spring MVC Frame works.

Hands on experience in using Eclipse IDE.

Working experience in scraper software like screen-scraper.

Basic knowledge of Ruby on Rails framework.

Good knowledge of Design Patterns like Singleton, Factory and MVC.

Experienced with the understanding of the principles and best practices of software Configuration Management (SCM) processes, which include compiling, packaging, deploying and Application Configurations like GIT, subversion (SVN) on Linux and Windows platforms.

Worked on SDLC methodologies like Agile, Waterfall and other processes.

## Work Experience

MasDat Solutions LLP as Software Engineer -Java /J2EE Mar 2018 to Jun 2020

Infocomm IT Services Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer Mar 2017 to Feb 2018

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Nagarjuna college of engineering & technology, Bangalore in 2016

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Java 1.5, JDBC	
JSP, Servlet	
Spring Boot, Spring MVC	
Hibernate, Query	
DSL, Ruby On Rails	
HTML, JavaScript	
Jquery, css, Ajax	
Bootstrap, Json, AngularJS	
PostgreSQL, Vertica, MySQL	
Eclipse, SVN, GIT, Maven	
WINDOWS, UNIX	
Apache Tomcat 9.0	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Kannada				
Bengali				

## **Projects**

Project Title: myReMeDi (My ReMeDi Patient Portal)

Client: NeuroSynaptic Communications

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2020 - Jun 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: Core Java, J2ee, Spring MVC, JSP, Servlet, JavaScript, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Vertica, AngularJS

Role Description: Requirement Analysis, coding and bug fixing.

Backend services

Additional to development, was also responsible for UI design and API integration.

Project Details: NeuroSynaptic Communications

Project Title: Smart Waste Management

Client: OnePlus Systems

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jul 2019 - Jun 2020 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: Core Java, J2ee, Spring Boot, JDBC, REST APIs, QueryDSL

Project Details: OnePlus Systems is the largest provider of Smart Waste Management software with a focus on waste fullness monitoring and analytics.

The main focus is to Empower companies with powerful insights and analytics to take control of their waste.

Major functionalities are Compactor monitoring and Container monitoring.

OnePlus provides real-time visibility and controls into the status levels of compactors calling for pick up only when its needed resulting in substantial cost savings and reduced carbon footprint.

OnePlus offers the broadest suite of IoT fill-level sensors that monitor many types of materials and mount easily to almost any container type.

Project Title: MDM (Master Data Management)

Client: Target Data

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Mar 2018 - Jun 2020

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Skill Used: Core Java, J2ee, Spring MVC, JSP, Servlet, JavaScript, JQuery, PostgreSQL, Vertica, Scrapper

Role Description: Requirement Analysis, coding and bug fixing.

**Data Scrapping** 

Perl and shell scripting

Additional to development, was also responsible for UI design.

Project Details: Target Data is a performance marketing agency fueled by data and focused on results. It requires an application which can help their data management services.

The main focus of target data is to target the pre movers. They Scrap data from different real estate sites and target clients and help them to shift.

Modules covered are administration, Dimension Management, Job Management, Data Loader, Client Services and File Delivery.

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time